When were you born?
你出生于哪一年？
If it was in the late nineties or early noughties, then you've been classified as being part of Generation Z.
如果是90年代末或21世纪初，那么你将被归类为Z世代的一员。
But what does that mean and is it necessary to group people according to their date of birth?
但这意味着什么，是否有必要根据出生日期对人群进行分组？
People have always been defined by their generation.
人们总是通过世代来定义自己。
We had the baby boomers of the 1960s, followed by Generation X and then Generation Y, often referred to as millennials, and the 'new kids on the block' are Generation Z – aged between 16 and 22.
我们有20世纪60年代的婴儿潮一代，接着是X世代，然后是Y世代（通常被称为千禧一代），而“新来的年轻人”是Z世代——年龄在16到22岁之间。
It's easy to classify these young people as being the same, sharing the same attitudes towards life – but is that fair?
很容易将这些年轻人归为一类，并认为他们对生活有相同的态度——但这公平吗？
A survey by the BBC's youth radio channel, Radio One, found that people from Generation Z, informally called 'Z-ers', may be viewed by others as shallow digital natives, incapable of real-world friendships.
BBC青年广播频道Radio One的一项调查发现，Z世代（非正式称为“Z世代人”）可能被他人视为肤浅的数字原住民，无法建立现实世界的友谊。
But they actually view themselves as hardworking, entrepreneurial and about to change the world for the better.
但他们实际上认为自己勤奋、有创业精神，并即将让世界变得更好。
It's an ambitious aim.
这是一个雄心勃勃的目标。
The previous generation, born between the mid-1980s and late 1990s - the millennials - were also thought to have these characteristics.
上一代人（出生于20世纪80年代中期至90年代末的千禧一代）也曾被认为具有这些特点。
But according to Hiral Patel, an analyst from Barclays, many people view this new generation as "mini-millennials".
但巴克莱分析师希拉尔・帕特尔表示，许多人将这新一代视为“迷你千禧一代”。
She told the BBC that Z-ers are different "they have their own set of values and preferences which consumer brands need to cater for.
她告诉BBC，Z世代不同，“他们有自己的价值观和偏好，消费品牌需要迎合这些。
Our research found that Gen Z are tech-innate, hyper-informed consumers, and extremely savvy."
我们的研究发现，Z世代是天生懂技术、信息高度灵通的消费者，并且极其精明。”
It's true to say that technology is playing an important part in the lives of Generation Z, particularly in the area of social media.
的确，技术在Z世代的生活中扮演着重要角色，尤其是在社交媒体领域。
In fact they have not known life without it and using it to communicate, share ideas and campaign is second nature – it’s their norm.
事实上，他们从未经历过没有技术的生活，使用技术交流、分享想法和发起活动是第二天性——这是他们的常态。
It means they have more of a say on what we eat, drink and buy than any generation before them.
这意味着他们在饮食和购物方面比之前任何一代都更有话语权。
These young people certainly need to be listened to by retailers and businesses – they are the people with time on their hands and money.
零售商和企业当然需要倾听这些年轻人的声音——他们有时间也有购买力。
But being a Z-er comes with pressure.
但作为Z世代也伴随着压力。
One young person told the BBC survey "many people in Generation Z have mental health issues because they're unsure what the future will bring."
一位年轻人在BBC调查中表示：“许多Z世代有心理健康问题，因为他们不确定未来会带来什么。”
The future always brings uncertainties but maybe there is pressure for this generation to be the most successful ever.
未来总是充满不确定性，但这一代人可能面临着成为最成功一代的压力。
If you're one of them, how do you feel about your future?
如果你是他们中的一员，你对自己的未来有何感受？